

CRISTIAN **Cartog** NIOR SOFTWARE IGINEER / TECHNICAL

+40 744 423 988 cristiancartog@gmail.com Sibiu, Romania

SKILLS

Back-End: Spring Framework (Core,

JaxRs, JPA

Java, Javascript, Typescript

Front-End: Angular 5, Angular 1, JQuery, CSS, HTML, DB: Mongo, Oracle, Exasol, MySql,

Boot, Data, Security, Web), EJB 3.1,

Elasticsearch Jira, Confluence, Jenkins

Git, SVN

Maven, Gradle, Npm, Ant

Nomad, Docker

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Certified Expert, Java EE 6 Persistence API Developer (2013)

Sun Certified Developer for Java Web Services 5 (2010)

Sun Certified Web Component Developer for J2EE 5 (2009)

Sun Certified Java Programmer for Java

6 (2009) Cisco Certified Network Associate

(2009)

EDUCATION BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN

AUTOMATION AND

COMPUTER SCIENCE

"POLITEHNICA" UNIVERSITY

2009

WEBSITES &

SOCIAL LINKS

OF TIMISOARA

linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cristia n-cartog-4ba98a66/ github:

https://github.com/cristiancartog

ABOUT ME

interested in remote work.

I am a consultant / contractor / freelancer with 14 years of experience, only

I help companies around the world implement maintainable, scalable and efficient distributed systems.

Let's connect and discuss how I can help your business!

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / TECHNICAL LEAD

WORK EXPERIENCE

issues to be solved preemptively

WINDELN.DE | SIBIU MAY 2016 - PRESENT

PIM: The company uses it's own product information management system which has a few issues: badly implemented, unscalable, untested, generated lots of data

- increased the product processing speed by 120% by eliminating unnecessary conversions and migrating it to the newer versions of mongo and Elasticsearch. increased product validation throughput by 600% by rewriting the validation
- logic, moving it in a separate service and deploying it on multiple machines
- reduced the technical debt by 95% (according to SonarQube) and lead a team of
- angular, Junit, mockito, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, maven, jenkins, nomad, git.

KIM: The company has it's own customer care application used by on/off-site

employees to quickly solve customer issues regarding orders, products, vouchers,

coupons, personal information, loyalty points, transactions and invoices, all during phone conversations.

reduced agents' call time by 30% by implementing a feature that enables order

• improved agents' productivity by 10% by providing easy access to detailed customer information in the UI

- reduced technical debt by 90% (as reported by SonarQube) and mentored 2
- developers

Groovy, Angular 1.5, Junit, mockito, MongoDB, maven, jenkins, nomad, GIT.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / TECHNICAL LEAD

 reduced decision maker's time by 50% by implementing batch processes that would automatically do employee-to-job role assignments

overall the application would save 80% of the managers' time spent on employee skill evaluation. The company has around 350.000 employees.

implemented 20% of the UI and core services and utilities

so the client wanted to migrate it to a newer technology stack. • lead a team of 4 developers, maintained the old system, and initiated the

saved 10% of the user's time by implementing the final feature of the old

in the banking sector. It was built on old, deprecated and proprietary technology,

Skills used: Java 7, JSF 2.1 with PrimeFaces 5, Wildfly 8, JPA, Hibernate, Oracle DB, proprietary technology (DI framework, ORM framework, UI component suite) ant, maven, SVN

MCC (Mopay Configuration Center): The client wanted all company office processes (user management, contract definitions, banking data management, package filtering, etc) to be done through one unified interface: a web application that would simulate a desktop environment (multiple windows, taskbar, start

reduced back-end latency by 50% through improved ORM mappings and better

• implemented 50% of the features and 70% of the core services and utilities

menu, control panel and notifications).

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

MINDMATICS LABS | SIBIU MAY 2012 - AUG 2014

JPA queries.

business logic

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

POLISANO | SIBIU AUG 2011 - APR 2012

application

recurring issues

SVN

migration.

 reduced the application load time by 80% through a build configuration that generated a compressed, minified and obfuscated UI artifact. Skills used: Java 6, Spring 3 (core, mvc, security), JPA (with Hibernate), SQL, oracle DB, tomcat 7, ExtJs 4.2, HTML, CSS3, junit, gradle, SVN, jenkins.

responsive. developed 50% of the charts and graphs the client would see and 30% of the

• reduced by 50% the response time of UI product classification tree component

through better data modeling and improved traversal method

 reduced technical debt by 45% and improved test code coverage by 40% Skills used: Java 6, Spring 3, tomcat 7, SQL, Oracle DB, Exasol DB, JDBC, JavaScript, ExtJs 4.2, HTML, CSS3, junit, gradle, SVN, jenkins

permissions, better response time and most of all, stability.

saved 6% of users' time, daily, by not having the constant downtime I introduced the concept of build tools (ant), feature tracking system (Jira), source code versioning (SVN), refactoring and good programming principles, patterns and practices in a clueless IT department.

Skills used: Java 6, JSF 2.1 (with Primefaces 5), HTML, CSS, Wildfly, MySQL, ant,

Vacations & Travel Agents: These 2 internal applications, a vacation management system and a time/route/client/offer tracking system needed only maintenance,

but this quickly became too time-consuming because of the poor quality of the reduced the codebase by 55% and improved application load time by 15%

through massive refactoring and usage of OOP concepts and best practices

• saved 5% of my time and 15% of the users' time by eliminating some of the

ant, SVN SOFTWARE DEVELOPER OCE | TIMISOARA AUG 2008 - JUL 2011

JPUI: The client wanted a full rewrite of a wide-format printer panel UI because of licensing issues in the UI library on the current version. The project was estimated for 9 months for 3 developers (and had a pessimistic aura as the initial

saved 22% of the budget by delivering the whole application 2 months earlier

Chinook: The client was developing a rich UI for high speed, high volume document printers and I was part of a team of 10 developers building the new UI.

saved 20% of an operators' workload by implementing a UI wizard that would

developed 60% of the components in the OTTK library, a Swing LoogAndFeel based on Metal, which would become the standard component library for

Skills used: Java 5, servlets, JSP, tomcat 6, MySQL, HTML, CSS2, javascript, jQuery,

refactoring and better use of Swing reduced technical debt to 0 (according to FindBugs and PMD)

improved response time by 50%, and reduced codebase by 40% through

implementation lasted 2.5 years with 5 developers).

supervised and mentored 2 colleagues

Skills used: Java 5, Swing, Junit, mockito, XML

guide them in fixing runtime printer issues

DEC 2006 - JUL 2008

- saved 5% of the product owner's time by implementing a build-time translation processor
- JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER CONTINENTAL AG | TIMISOARA

to be installed in Volkswagen, Seat and Skoda cars, starting 2009.

Skills used: Java 5, Swing, XML, DTD, XSLT, XSD, Xpath, Jaxb, Junit

"chinook" and subsequent printer UIs in the company.

improved RVC usability by 10% by fixing crucial issues in RVC that were constantly causing back screens improved OPS usability by 50% by building the picture-in-picture functionality

TAE (Test Automation Environment): Test Automation Environment is a test

Eclipse plugin with editor support for syntax highlighting, code suggestions and

boosted test writers' productivity by 50% through the development of an

OPS & RVC: The client needed help fixing issues on the Optical Parking System and Rear View Camera control modules for the Radio Navigation System that was

runner/debugger capable of interpreting DSL instructions to command a car engine HIL device. The client wanted to assist engineers in writing the tests.

processing library for a test generator tool

Skills used: Java 5, Eclipse RCP, python 2.7, wxPython, SVN

completion, project management, outline view and debugger integration with TAE • further saved 30% of the test writers' time by implementing a UI and data

improved test coverage by 60%

Skills used: Java 5, OSGI, jMock

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Expenses: I built an android app to track personal expenses and show insightful

charts and tables based on cash outflow.

Skills used: Android SDK, Gradle. Git

VOLUNTEER WORK

based on predefined templates.

AUG 2014 - AUG 2016

TIMISOARA JUN 2006 - JUL 2006 MAP Newsletter: I joined the local Microsoft Academic Program and as part of a team of 5 developers created a newsletter web application. This saved 80% of the administrators' time by enabling them to quickly compose and send newsletters

Skill used: C#, ASP.NET, Visual SourceSafe, MS SQL Server

issues and was hard to maintain. A new PIM implementation was needed.

reduced the indexing process from 4h to 10 min by creating a new reindexing service

5 developers.

Skills used: Java, Spring Boot, activemq, rabbitmq, javascript, typescript, groovy,

Skills used: Java 8, Spring Boot 2.1, activemq, rabbitmq, Javascript, Typescript,

ROPARDO | SIBIU AUG 2014 - APR 2016

JRA (Job Role Advisor): The company needed an application that would allow managers to set possible career paths and job roles to employees based on their

skill sets.

Skills used: Java 7, EJB 3.1, JaxRs, Javascript, Dojo 8, WebSphere, mybatis, DB2, ant, IBM "Rational" tool suite Flex Finance: The client had an old, complex report generation suite heavily used

system: an in-browser excel editing for report configuration created 30% of the core services, defined the multi-module project structure and built the portal application

Mopay Cockpit: This cash flow and KPI monitoring application is the main interface for the company's clients. The company needed it to improve client retention and build trust so the user interface had to be sharp, polished and very

Reports: The client had a very old, unstable, insecure and unappealing reporting application consisting of 170 pages. He wanted a new one that would also provide basic features such as security, content restrictions based on user roles and

• implemented 100% of the required functionality and provided clear guidelines

• 30% faster report generation through better queries, caches, pagination and sorting mechanisms; 70% codebase reduction compared to the older